Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/edgarguzman-390a1a164 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Team Leadership
Teamwork
Problem Solving

Edgar Guzman

BDR @ Regal | Squad Leader | US Marine Non-Comissioned Officer and Jazz drummer

New York, New York, United States

Summary

As a seasoned sales professional, I have honed my skills at Jitjatjo and Lenscrafters where I was responsible for developing new business, building relationships with clients/customers, and exceeding sales targets. During my time in the military, I served as a manager and leader, gaining invaluable experience in team building, strategic planning, and decision-making. I proudly served my country in the Marines, exemplifying discipline and dedication to duty.

In addition, I'm a jazz drummer, bringing that unique flavor to everywhere I work- the ability to think on my feet, improvise and adapt to changing circumstances, and excel in high-pressure situations. These skills will be invaluable to my current role as a Business Development Representative at Regal.io, where I am responsible for identifying new opportunities, nurturing relationships with clients, and driving revenue growth.

My background in sales, management, and the military has taught me the importance of discipline, perseverance, and teamwork. These qualities have helped me succeed in all aspects of my life, both personally and professionally, and I am committed to using my experience to continue making a positive impact in the world around me.

Experience

Regal.io BDR April 2023 - Present (1 year 1 month) New York City Metropolitan Area

United States Marine Corps Infantry Squad Leader November 2020 - Present (3 years 6 months)

- Led a team of 12+ Marines as a Non-Commissioned Officer, overseeing training plans and managing team initiatives while staying on budget and schedule.
- Implemented an instructional curriculum that was adopted company-wide.
- Achieved meritorious promotion to Non-Commissioned Officer after leading a squad to be the highest rated in the company during a joint training exercise.
- Coordinated logistics, commander's requirements, resources, and educational material to improve individual and team performance.
- Leveraged experience as a squad leader and non-commissioned officer to develop project management skills, including budget and schedule management, that can be applied to civilian environments to ensure efficient and effective project completion.

Jitjatjo

SDR

February 2022 - March 2023 (1 year 2 months)

- Conducted 5,000+ cold calls, emails, and LinkedIn messages.
- Collaborated with compliance, client success, and talent acquisition to assist in implementing software
- Coordinated with marketing to optimize and create campaigns.
- Achieved 35% engagement rate through A/B testing, intent data analysis, and market research.
- Developed and enhanced project management skills through hands-on experience as a Sales Development Representative, leading to improved campaign coordination and successful client onboarding.

LensCrafters

Sales Representative

July 2021 - February 2022 (8 months)

Yonkers, New York, United States

- Engaging high volumes of customers and closing an average of 15,000\$
 worth of sales per week.
- Assisting the store manager with administrative paperwork, shipping out customer orders, and maintaining store cleanliness.
- Performed 20% above quota for the average cost of spectacle during the 4th quarter of 2021.

Surprise Lake Camp Manager of Filmography June 2019 - August 2020 (1 year 3 months)

- Directed and supervised a team of three interns to capture and edit videos showcasing the campers' daily activities.
- Organized and facilitated film and photography activities for campers.
- Collaborated closely with the camp's president to achieve social media goals and promote the camp's brand.
- Increased video viewership by 15% that summer.

IATSE

Stagehand

August 2017 - July 2020 (3 years)

- · Worked freelance for the IATSE union.
- Moved in/out all the sound, lighting, and stage equipment.
- Met the expectations on adaptability and efficiency under massive constraints within 6 hours at most.
- Events included setting up for Marvel's Universe Live show, Tiesto, and the VAP Opera.

Self-employed

Freelance Filmmaker

October 2017 - March 2020 (2 years 6 months)

- Found, contacted, and engaged clients within the Hudson Valley area.
- Managed personal schedules and secured gigs such as music videos, weddings, sporting events, music concerts, advertisements, and theatre performances.
- Negotiated prices, traveled to locations, and filmed/edited all the materials.

Fisher Center at Bard

Carpenter and Stage Hand

February 2017 - March 2020 (3 years 2 months)

- Worked to build, maintain, and uphold a local theatre.
- Worked with designers to set up over 30 shows throughout 3 years.

Education

Bard College

Bachelor of Fine Arts - BFA, Jazz/Jazz Studies · (2016 - 2020)

Activity

04/18/2024, Imeila Fonua added candidate to BDR- Test Sample